<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bayesian on Dead Reckoning Analytics and Consulting</title>
    <link>/tags/bayesian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bayesian on Dead Reckoning Analytics and Consulting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/bayesian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Variance in Multilevel Models Using the Riverplot Package</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/01/19/2019-01-19-visualizing-variance-in-multilevel-models-using-the-riverplot-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/01/19/2019-01-19-visualizing-variance-in-multilevel-models-using-the-riverplot-package/</guid>
      <description>Spurred on by Alex Shackman, I have been working to figure out a good way to visualize different sources of variation in momentary mood. The most common way of visually depicting variance decompositions from the sort of multilevel models we used to analyze our data is a stacked bar plot. So that seemed like a good place to start.
Figure 1. Stacked Barplot of Model Variance Decomposition
 Now, choosing a color scheme that screams “HI I’M A COLOR!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaussian Process Imputation/Forecast Models</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/05/21/2018-05-21-gaussian-process-imputation-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/05/21/2018-05-21-gaussian-process-imputation-models/</guid>
      <description>A well-established set of problems emerges when attempting to analyze non-stationary univariate time series (i.e., the signal’s mean and/or variance changes over time). A common approach is to impose some stationarity on the data so that certain modeling techniques can provide allow a research to make some predictions (e.g., ARIMA models). The selection of the appropriate assumptions to make when forcing a time series into stationarity is difficult to automate in many circumstances, requiring that a researcher evaluate competing models.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
