<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Processing on Matthew Barstead, Ph.D.: Research, Repository, &amp; Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/data-processing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Processing on Matthew Barstead, Ph.D.: Research, Repository, &amp; Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Matthew Barstead</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Alive! First Evidence that IBI VizEdit Works</title>
      <link>/post/it-s-alive-first-evidence-that-ibi-vizedit-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/it-s-alive-first-evidence-that-ibi-vizedit-works/</guid>
      <description>It is official. The program I have spent the better part of a year working on, the very centerpiece of my dissertation, works. Or at least, early indicators are in, and based on 22 cases, some of which required a great deal of manual editing, the program is returning estimates in line with expectations.
Backing up, as I trip a little over my excitement, IBI VizEdit is an Rshiny application I created to help our lab process and edit heart rate data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RMarkdown is the Most Powerful Codebook Maker You Can Find for Your Datasets</title>
      <link>/post/rmarkdown-is-the-most-powerful-codebook-maker-you-can-find-for-your-datasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rmarkdown-is-the-most-powerful-codebook-maker-you-can-find-for-your-datasets/</guid>
      <description>You worked hard to collect, clean, and process your data. Now your dataset is finally ready for that final step. That put a bow on it and send it to all your colleagues phase. You are at that moment when you release a deep sigh of relief at the end of the hard (sometimes underappreciated) work of data wrangling. Now you have to make something that communicates all that you have done.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>