<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Individual-Risk on Matt Barstead&#39;s Research, Blog, &amp; Repository</title>
    <link>https://mgb-research.netlify.com/tags/individual-risk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Individual-Risk on Matt Barstead&#39;s Research, Blog, &amp; Repository</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Matthew Barstead</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mgb-research.netlify.com/tags/individual-risk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Callous Unemotional Meta-Analysis</title>
      <link>https://mgb-research.netlify.com/project/cu-meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mgb-research.netlify.com/project/cu-meta/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Callous-unemotional (CU) traits are central to our understanding of antisocial behavior, which is harmful, financially costly to society, and hard to treat. Theoretical and diagnostic models define CU traits based on a lack of empathy, guilt, and prosociality. However, there has been no comprehensive quantitative synthesis of results to support this claim, nor any examination of whether associations differ by age, gender, sample type, or informant. Given its centrality to our understanding and treatment of antisocial behavior, the time is ripe for a critical examination of the meaning of the CU traits construct, including associations with its purported underlying features of low empathy, guilt, and prosociality, and potential demographic and methodological moderators of these associations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual Risk for Anxiety and Depression</title>
      <link>https://mgb-research.netlify.com/project/dn_research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mgb-research.netlify.com/project/dn_research/</guid>
      <description>Cell phones are ubiquitous on college campuses, annoying many an instructor who looks back at a classroom filled with young adults enamored with their black mirrors (and yes I am still very impressed with the underlying meaning of the hit Netflix series&amp;rsquo; title). As others have in the past Dr. Alex Shackman, sought to use the constant presence of cell phones to better understand the daily lives of individuals.
Using college students as subjects is often decried as laziness and viewed somewhat skeptically as investigators reaching out to a subject pool that is readily available to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Anxiety in Early Childhood</title>
      <link>https://mgb-research.netlify.com/project/turtlemd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mgb-research.netlify.com/project/turtlemd/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Ken Rubin has spent the majority of his career studying the causes, correlates, and consequences of childhood anxiety and social withdrawal. As a result of an ongoing collaboration with Dr. Andrea Chronis-Tuscano, a clinical psychology professor and researcher, and in consultation with Dr. Rob Coplan, this career has recently been translated into the creation of an early intervention program. The intervention, named the Turtle Program, simultaneously targets maladaptive parenting behaviors known to maintain and exacerbate childhood anxiety in addition to anxious and inhibited children&amp;rsquo;s social skills and emotion regulation deficits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Withdrawal Meta-Analysis</title>
      <link>https://mgb-research.netlify.com/project/sw-meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mgb-research.netlify.com/project/sw-meta/</guid>
      <description>Are the terms anxious withdrawal, anxious solitude, behavioral inhibition, shyness-sensitivity, interchangeable? Are peer, parent, teacher, and self-perceptions of social withdrawal measuring the same thing? To date, researchers have relied on narrative arguments to build a case for or againts correspondence among the terms and measurement approaches used by developmental scientists interested in these and related constructs. I want to let the data speak for itself, and I am conducting a meta-analysis to do just that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>