<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IBI-VizEdit on Matt Barstead&#39;s Research, Blog, &amp; Repository</title>
    <link>/tags/ibi-vizedit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IBI-VizEdit on Matt Barstead&#39;s Research, Blog, &amp; Repository</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Matthew Barstead</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ibi-vizedit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaussian Process Imputation Models</title>
      <link>/project/gp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/gp/</guid>
      <description>I have become increasingly interested in the use of Gaussian process models as a tool for forecasting and imputation with univariate time series. See my blog post on the topic for more information and a toy forecasting problem.
I am currently working on a study examining the effectiveness of these models in imputing heart rate data that has been severely corrupted by artifact - to the point that there is not &amp;ldquo;enough&amp;rdquo; true signal remaining to do much of anything with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBI VizEdit</title>
      <link>/project/ibi-vizedit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ibi-vizedit/</guid>
      <description>IBI VizEdit is a program built using RShiny. It is designed to assist in the manual editing of inter-beat interval files that are derived from photoplethysmogram (PPG) recordings. Unlike the electrocardiogram signal (EKG or ECG), PPG signals are characterized by a slow-moving waveform, which presents a different set of challenges when the true signal becomes corrupted by motion artefacts and other sources of noise.
Though increasingly popular due to their ease of use, most heart rate editing software that exists to date was designed and optimized for the detection and editing of inter-beat interval files derived from ECG signals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>